computer science

- Yohannestsegaye1212@gmail.com
- Addis Abeba, Ethiopia
- +251 91 212 8122

Languages

English

writing: Very Good Speaking: Very Good Listing: Very Good

Amharic

Speaking :Native writing : Native Listing: Native

Social networks

in @YohannesTsegaye

@YohannesTsegaye

Project

Hotel management system for Ras Dejen Hotel

Reserving room, food ordering, Generating Report generating ,online payment, special offer(discount),update price, get conformation for the reserved room or food , two step verification check the food is delivered, rejected or pending and ask reason why reject.

Department placement for Debark university

place Student Department Based on There Choice and GPA login by there password see there placement can give a feedback about there placement

Reference

Head to Department of computer science, Debark university Email:- abebawagegndtu@gmail.com

Emebet Zerfu

Knowledge Management Lead, IPHC-E emebet.zerfu.@iphce.org

Animut Mesfin

System Librarian and ICT Expert, IPHC-E animut.mesfin.@iphce.org

Education

BSc in computer science

From September 2020 to July 2023 Debark University Gonder, AM, Ethiopia CGPA:3.57/4.0

Relevant course

deep understanding about Data Structures & algorithm, Computer Organization and Architecture, Database Systems, Computer Networks, Distributed Systems, Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML),understand Programming logic and computer Graphics

GPT program

From June 2023 to August 2023

TE Network Solution Addis Ababa, AA, Ethiopia

At IE Network Solutions, I trained in full-stack development using **React (TypeScript)** and **Node.js (NestJS)**. I built responsive UIs, developed secure APIs, and worked with **MongoDB** for backend data handling.

I also integrated **GPT AI** into web apps, creating smart features like chatbots and content generators using OpenAI's API. This handson experience sharpened my coding, problem-solving, and AI integration skills—preparing me to build real-world, intelligent web applications.

Certification

From May 2023 to June 2023 - -

have completed certified courses on **JavaScript** and the **MERN stack** through **Udemy**, where I learned how to build full web applications using **Node.js**, **React**, **and Nest.js**. These hands-on courses helped me develop real-world skills in both frontend and backend development.

These learning experiences have equipped me with the tools and confidence to build full-stack, modern web applications.

Work experience

Data Encoder

From September 2024 to December 2024

POESS(Private organization social security) Addis Ababa Administration, Ethiopia

Data Encoding, Data Verification and Validation ,Record Maintenance

Reporting, Communication and Support, Confidentiality, System Management and Troubleshooting

Intern IT Expert

From March 2024 to September 2024 **IIPHC-E** Addis Ababa Data Encoder Web Analyst

IT Assistant

From August 2022 to September 2022 commercial Bank of Ethiopia District office Gonder computer maintenance,printer maintenance,maintenance and configuration of network equipment,ATM maintenance

Computer skills

Advanced Computer Skills

includes Linux, Ubuntu and Window Server (2016), Google workspace

Skills

programing skills

C++,Java,Python,,MySQ,Angular Html,Css,Php,Java script,wordpress MERN Stack(Mongodb,Express,React,Nodejs)